<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[BOHUSLAV RATAY]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[BOHUSLAV RATAY]]></description>
        <link>http://bohuslavrattay.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 23:57:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://bohuslavrattay.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 23:57:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Czech-American conductor Bohuslav Rattay is a busy ambassador for classical music, working with orchestras across the globe to produce symphonic works of all kinds to a diverse audience. The newly appointed Music Director of the El Paso Symphony Orchestr]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Czech-American conductor <strong>Bohuslav Rattay</strong> is a busy ambassador for classical music, working with orchestras across the globe to produce symphonic works of all kinds to a diverse audience. The newly appointed Music Director of the El Paso Symphony Orchestra also serves as Music Director for the Midland Symphony Orchestra and the Lake Charles Symphony Orchestra. As he gains a reputation as one of the finest young talents of his generation, Mr. Rattay combines impassioned and virtuosic musicianship with a determination to bring great music into the lives of all people.</p>,<p>An enthusiastic promoter for classical music, Mr. Rattay strives to bring the traditional and innovative together in a manner exciting and fresh for his audience. He is renowned for his unique concert programs, incorporating special audience discussions and including multi-media elements. He is also appreciated for his passion for the classics, with special appreciation often given to his insightful understanding of the music of his native Bohemia. Rattay has been praised for his ability to communicate the depth of a diverse range of music to his audience, for the classics, “Rattay is certainly the man for Tchaikovsky’s fourth” (Charleston Today, 2011), and for the fashionable, “Watching him conduct is like watching a painter creating rich imagery to live music on a large canvas” (El Paso Times, 2013). His intelligent and vast programming allows him to connect to a broad range of audience, creating new symphony-goers while entertaining the enthusiasts.</p>,<p>Rattay’s talents and abilities are highly praised. He is internationally acclaimed by critics and audiences alike for his fresh and inspired musical interpretations. He has received accolades for his “vibrant” performances and his “elegant panache,” (Charleston City Paper, 2009), his ability to lead the orchestra with his “infectious zest and physicality,” (Midland Daily News 2013), and his one-of-a-kind artistry, bringing “personal perspective… that will be remembered for many years,” (Duluth News Tribune, 2012).</p>,<p>His overflowing passion for classical music is highly solicited, recently appearing as guest conductor with the Colorado Symphony, the Duluth-Superior Symphony, the Hilton Head Symphony, and the Teplice Philharmonic in his native Czech Republic. Other recent engagements include the Virginia Symphony, West Michigan Symphony, Prague's Dvořák Symphony Orchestra, and the Charleston (SC) Symphony, where he received several critical accolades. He has also conducted the National Symphony Orchestra as part of the National Conducting Institute and was selected by the American Symphony Orchestra League to participate in its Conducting Fellowship Program.</p>,<p>Believing in the power of education, Mr. Rattay is a committed pedagogue of the younger generations. He has been a music faculty member of the College of William and Mary, Ball State University, and is a frequent guest conductor of All-State and youth orchestras across the United States. The combination of his youthful energy along with his conducting skills make him highly valued as an inspirational mentor.</p>,<p>Mr. Rattay holds degrees from the Prague Conservatory, Rice University and the Peabody Institute of Music. He names Gustav Meier, Larry Rachleff, Benjamin Kamins, and Neeme Jarvi as his most influential teachers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://bohuslavrattay.com/biography/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2b130b44-ddbf-4d03-9500-7210b8f19907</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 05:51:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RESUME]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>RESUME</h1>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJwDAAAAAAE" height="10"></iframe>,<ul><li><strong>2013-19 Music Director, El Paso Symphony Orchestra, TX</strong></li><li><strong>2012-18 Music Director, Midland Symphony Orchestra, MI</strong></li><li><strong>2010-18 Music Director, Lake Charles Symphony Orchestra, LA</strong></li></ul>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJwDAAAAAAE" height="8"></iframe>,<ul><li>2017 Guest Conductor, <em>Irving Symphony Orchestra</em>, TX</li><li>2016 Guest Conductor, <em>Antalya Symphony Orchestra, </em>Turkey</li><li>2016 Guest Conductor, <em>Lubbock Symphony Orchestra</em>, TX</li><li>2015 Guest Conductor, <em>University of Texas at El Paso Symphony Orchestra</em>, TX</li><li>2015/16 Guest Conductor, <em>Bogota Sinfonica de Colombia</em></li><li>2015 Guest Conductor, <em>Cypress Chamber Orchestra</em>, Cypress, TX</li><li>2013 Guest Conductor, <em>Teplice Philharmonic</em>, Czech Republic</li><li>2013 Guest Conductor, <em>Rainier Symphony Orchestra</em>, WA</li><li>2012 Guest Conductor, <em>Colorado Symphony Orchestra</em>, Denver, CO</li><li>2012 Guest Conductor, <em>Duluth Superior Symphony Orchestra</em>, Duluth, MN</li><li>2012 Guest Conductor, <em>Hilton Head Symphony Orchestra</em>, Hilton Head, SC</li><li>2006-12 Music Director, <em>Muncie Symphony Orchestra</em>, Muncie, IN</li><li>2006-12 Music Director, <em>Ball State University Symphony Orchestras and Opera</em></li><li>2009-11 Guest Conductor, <em>Charleston Symphony Orchestra</em>, Charleston, SC</li><li>2010 Guest Conductor, <em>West Michigan Symphony Orchestra</em>, Muskegon, MI</li><li>2006-8 Guest Conductor, <em>Dvořák Symphony Orchestra</em>, Prague, CZ</li><li>2007 Guest Conductor, <em>Cernigov Symphony Orchestra</em>, Ukraine</li><li>2007 Guest Conductor, <em>Alabama All-State Symphony Orchestra</em>, AL</li><li>2006 Guest Conductor, <em>Virginia Symphony Orchestra</em>, Norfolk, VA</li><li>2006 Guest Conductor, <em>UT Austin Symphony Orchestra</em>, Austin, TX</li><li>2005-6 Music Director, <em>College of William and Mary</em>, Williamsburg, VA</li><li>2005 Assistant Conductor, <em>Peabody Symphony Orchestra</em>, Baltimore, MD</li><li>2004 Guest Conductor, <em>St. Petersburg Academic Orchestra</em>, Russia</li><li>2004 Guest Conductor, <em>Moscow Chamber Orchestra</em>, Russia</li><li>2004 Guest Conductor, <em>Parnu City Symphony Orchestra</em>, Estonia</li><li>2002 Guest Conductor, <em>Manchester Symphony Orchestra</em>, CT</li></ul>,<ul><li><strong>WORKSHOPS</strong></li></ul>,<ul><li>2007-8 Instructor, <em>International Conducting Workshop</em>, Zlin, CZ</li><li>2005 <em>National Conducting Institute</em>, J.F. Kennedy Center, Washington D.C.</li><li>2004 <em>Neeme Jarvi </em>Summer Academy in Parnu, Estonia</li><li>2004 <em>Kurt Masur</em> Conducting Seminar, Manhattan School of Music in New York</li><li>2004 <em>Donald Thulean</em> ASOL Conducting Workshop in Buffalo with <em>JoAnn Falleta</em></li><li>2004 California Conducting Workshop with <em>Daniel Lewis </em>and<em> Donald Thulean</em></li><li>2003 <em>Donald Thulean</em> ASOL Conducting Workshop in Chicago with <em>Carl St.Clair</em></li><li>2002 International Workshop for Conductors in Kromeriz, Czech Republic</li></ul>,<ul><li><strong>AWARDS</strong></li></ul>,<ul><li>2013 Judge, Concert Artist Guild <em>Victor Elmaleh Competition</em>, NYC</li><li>2005 Host of ‘<em>Colonial Classics</em>’ radio show, WCWM 90.9 FM, Williamsburg, VA</li><li>2005 <em>Malko Conducting Competition</em> for young conductors, Copenhagen, Denmark</li><li>2004 Peabody Symphony Orchestra Assistantship, Peabody Conservatory, MD</li><li>2004 Peabody Career Development Grant, Peabody Conservatory, Baltimore, MD</li></ul>,<ul><li><strong>EDUCATION</strong></li></ul>,<ul><li>2002-2005 GPD, <em>Gustav Meier </em>and<em> Markand Thakar</em>, Peabody Conservatory, Baltimore, MD</li><li>2001-2002 <em>Christopher Zimmerman</em>, Hartt School of Music, Hartford, CT</li><li>1995-1997 MM, <em>Larry Rachleff and Benjamin Kamins</em>, Shepherd School of Music, Rice University, Houston, TX</li><li>1986-1991 BA, Prague Conservatory of Music, Czech Republic</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://bohuslavrattay.com/resume/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b5ad4b20-ab7e-4692-98e4-066357f624a9</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 21:13:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2017/18 CONCERT SCHEDULE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2017/18 CONCERT SCHEDULE</h1>,<p>September 15/16 2017 - <strong>Le Quattro Staggioni</strong></p>,<ul><li><strong>Chloe Trevor, violin</strong></li><li>Vivaldi Le Quattro Staggioni</li><li>Piazzolla Four Seasons in Buenos Aires</li><li>Korsakov Snow Maiden Suite</li><li>Stravinsky Firebird Suite</li></ul>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJwDAAAAAAE" height="20"></iframe>,<p>October 20/21 2017 - <strong>Beethoven, Bartok and Beer</strong></p>,<ul><li><strong>Yefim Bronfman, piano</strong></li><li>Beethoven piano concerto no.4</li><li>Bartok Concerto for Orchestra</li></ul>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJwDAAAAAAE" height="20"></iframe>,<p>November 17/18 2017 - <strong>Music of John Williams</strong></p>,<ul><li>ET: Adventures on Earth</li><li><strong>Concerto for Horn and Orchestra</strong></li><li>March from Raiders of the Lost Ark</li><li>Highlights from Jurassic park</li><li><strong>Concerto for Bassoon and Orchestra</strong></li><li>Star Wars Medley</li></ul>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJwDAAAAAAE" height="20"></iframe>,<p>February 23/24 2018 - <strong>UTEP Choral Collaboration</strong></p>,<ul><li>Beethoven Symphony No.7</li><li>Best of Requiems</li></ul>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJwDAAAAAAE" height="20"></iframe>,<p>April 13/14 2018 - <strong>Kurt Weill festival</strong></p>,<ul><li>Mack the knife</li><li>Seven deadly sins</li><li>Whitman songs</li><li>Broadway medley</li></ul>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJwDAAAAAAE" height="20"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://bohuslavrattay.com/201718-concert-schedule/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">27cf9b82-546b-41a7-b4a2-2a9929a449e8</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 21:40:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>